<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>William Orson Harris III Blog</title>
    <description>My base of opoerations on the internet</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Get better at Pokemon GO PVP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some tips to get better at Pokemon GO PVP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;study the current meta: acquaint yourself with the big players in the current meta. You can usually do this by keeping up with posts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/great-league-pvp-tier-list&quot;&gt;Gamepress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pokebattler.com/&quot;&gt;Pokebattler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gamepress.gg/pokemongo/gobattlesim&quot;&gt;gobattlesim&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know the IV-s of your Pokemon, you can do this with the appraise Pokemon button or using an external app like Calcy-IV. In a mirror match a Pokemon with a 15 attack will beat one with a 14 attack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Track your opponent’s Pokemon and his switches. For example if you find you are in a favorable position doing super-effective damage to opponent’s Pokemon with your quick attack they will likely swap out that Pokemon, if it was Altaria for example then say the words “Altaria in the back” so that you remember what will be showing back up again. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overcharging: this is one of the most surprising and frustrating aspects of advanced level play. Instead of unleashing your charged attacks as they become available you can “save them up”. This can appear as if your opponent is getting extra moves when you aren’t getting any but this is a subtle and powerful tactic of expert players. If you aren’t taking major damage from your opponent and you can afford to do it then do it. If timed correctly it can be devastating to your opponent. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to withdraw your Pokemon with a fully charged attack ready in the chamber, that way when you bring the Pokemon back into the battle he has a charged attack ready to fire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;b&gt;The extra shield&lt;/b&gt;”: if you have a Pokemon who is about to die and you are able to perform a swap, do it. Even if the Pokemon isn’t going to be useful in the battle you can use them as a 3rd shield. when your opponent it getting ready to unleash a charged attack and you are able to swap again, swap in your nearly dead Pokemon to take the hit instead, effectively it shielded your other Pokemon. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Damage types: use TMs and elite TMs to give your Pokemon as wide a spread of damage types as possible. Having the quick and both charged attacks all as a different type can be very effective. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to fight only with Pokemon that have a 15 attack stat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only fight with Pokemon that have two charged attacks, be trapped into just one damage type can lose you the game if your final match is against a Mon that is immune to your one damage type.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep in mind the game dynamic of swaps. Using this wisely is probably the single greatest characteristic that separates great players from merely good ones. Always remember that if you swap a Pokemon first then you are giving your opponent swap advantage and leaving yourself open to a “trade trap”. If you swap, for example into a Giratina, and your opponent has Togekiss, they can swap and destroy your Giratina with charm before your Giratina can even get off a single attack. Likewise if your opponent swaps first they have given you the swap advantage. Try to capitalize on it wisely. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No single team can beat all other teams. Because of this fact you need to have a couple of teams to swap between that are possibly similar but not the same. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oftentimes you can be trapped in “The mini-Meta” which is a level of PVP that seems to go against the main larger Meta. For example if Charizard is not a great performer in the general Meta but you find yourself facing and being beaten by charizard often, then you are trapped in a mini-Meta. Just make a slight adjustment to your team to cope with the Charizard and pretty soon you won’t be seeing Charizard any longer. Then you can return your effective team back to its most effective settings. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Wall and the Closer:&lt;/b&gt; There has been a very successful strategy circulating for over a year now called “The Wall and the Closer”, wherein your first Pokemon is a Wall i.e. a Pokemon with HUGE hitpoints and fairly resistant to most attacks by being mono-type. Some examples recently are Snorlax or Armored-Mewtwo. The strategy here is “&lt;b&gt;never shield, never swap&lt;/b&gt;” whenever feasible. This way you absorb your opponents attacks while saving your own shields and hopefully wearing down your opponents Mon and shields. Ideally you will wind up in a situation where you have two shields and your opponent has none. Then you can bring in the Closer, a Pokemon with a powerful finishing attack such as shadow-ball or earthquake. You can use your shields to protect your Mon while they charge up to the big finish and your opponent has to take the hits un-shielded. A benefit of this strategy is that you can potentially have two choices for your closer, which leads to the final point:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whenever possible, you should choose the 3-bar charge move and the other charged attack should be a big finisher (possibly earthquake or shadow-ball) that way you can have a choice of picking this Mon as either a pinch-hitter good for lots of short damage OR use them as a closer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 15:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pokemon/go/2021/01/17/Get-better-at-Pokemon-GO-PVP/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pokemon/go/2021/01/17/Get-better-at-Pokemon-GO-PVP/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can't wait to start reading this one!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Star-Wars-Light-Jedi-Republic/dp/0593157710/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=light+of+the+jedi&amp;amp;link_code=qs&amp;amp;qid=1610579914&amp;amp;sourceid=Mozilla-search&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;tag=mozilla-20&quot;&gt;Light of the Jedi: High Republic Book 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/light-of-the-jedi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ligh of the Jedi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of the Star Wars books. Have been having trouble lately finding time and concentration required
to read a book but I am actually excited about this one.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 15:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/star/wars/2021/01/13/Light-of-the-Jedi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/star/wars/2021/01/13/Light-of-the-Jedi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What people think programming is vs. how it actually is</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend JK from Japan saw this and he said it made him think of me. It hilarious how true it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HluANRwPyNo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 15:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/programming/2021/01/09/What-People-Think/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/programming/2021/01/09/What-People-Think/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Chess Game No Blunders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I used to think I was pretty good at chess, but now that I am getting back into it I am just happy to have a game
with no blunders.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;https://pgn.chessbase.com/CBReplay.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://pgn.chessbase.com/jquery-3.0.0.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://pgn.chessbase.com/cbreplay.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cbreplay&quot;&gt;

[Event &quot;Live Chess - chess&quot;]
[Site &quot;Chess.com&quot;]
[Date &quot;2021.01.08&quot;]
[Round &quot;?&quot;]
[White &quot;15953392&quot;]
[Black &quot;cgbharat&quot;]
[Result &quot;1-0&quot;]
[TimeControl &quot;600&quot;]
[WhiteElo &quot;1223&quot;]
[BlackElo &quot;1173&quot;]
[Termination &quot;15953392 won by checkmate&quot;]

1. e4 {[%clk 0:10:00][%timestamp 0]} 1... e6 {[%clk 0:10:00][%timestamp 0]} 2.
e5 {[%clk 0:09:58.3][%timestamp 17]} 2... d5 {[%clk 0:09:59][%timestamp 10]} 3.
exd6 {[%clk 0:09:56.4][%timestamp 19]} 3... cxd6 {[%clk 0:09:57.4][%timestamp
16]} 4. d4 {[%clk 0:09:53.7][%timestamp 27]} 4... d5 {[%clk
0:09:56.8][%timestamp 6]} 5. Nf3 {[%clk 0:09:48.3][%timestamp 54]} 5... a6
{[%clk 0:09:55.4][%timestamp 14]} 6. Bd3 {[%clk 0:09:44.1][%timestamp 42]} 6...
b5 {[%clk 0:09:53.9][%timestamp 15]} 7. a4 {[%clk 0:09:40.5][%timestamp 36]}
7... b4 {[%clk 0:09:42.5][%timestamp 114]} 8. Bd2 {[%clk 0:09:34.1][%timestamp
64]} 8... Nf6 {[%clk 0:09:38.6][%timestamp 39]} 9. Bg5 {[%clk
0:09:28.6][%timestamp 55]} 9... a5 {[%clk 0:09:33.2][%timestamp 54]} 10. Bb5+
{[%clk 0:09:24.9][%timestamp 37]} 10... Bd7 {[%clk 0:09:30.2][%timestamp 30]}
11. Bxd7+ {[%clk 0:09:22.1][%timestamp 28]} 11... Qxd7 {[%clk
0:09:28.9][%timestamp 13]} 12. Bxf6 {[%clk 0:09:19.6][%timestamp 25]} 12... gxf6
{[%clk 0:09:26.6][%timestamp 23]} 13. O-O {[%clk 0:09:18][%timestamp 16]} 13...
Bg7 {[%clk 0:09:21.1][%timestamp 55]} 14. c3 {[%clk 0:09:12.1][%timestamp 59]}
14... bxc3 {[%clk 0:09:14.8][%timestamp 63]} 15. Nxc3 {[%clk
0:09:10.3][%timestamp 18]} 15... Nc6 {[%clk 0:09:01.5][%timestamp 133]} 16. Qb3
{[%clk 0:09:05.2][%timestamp 51]} 16... Rb8 {[%clk 0:08:54.1][%timestamp 74]}
17. Qc2 {[%clk 0:08:59][%timestamp 62]} 17... f5 {[%clk 0:08:47.4][%timestamp
67]} 18. Rad1 {[%clk 0:08:53.4][%timestamp 56]} 18... Nb4 {[%clk
0:08:31.3][%timestamp 161]} 19. Qd2 {[%clk 0:08:45.7][%timestamp 77]} 19... O-O
{[%clk 0:08:13.2][%timestamp 181]} 20. Nb5 {[%clk 0:08:38.8][%timestamp 69]}
20... Rfc8 {[%clk 0:07:42.3][%timestamp 309]} 21. Rc1 {[%clk
0:08:35.2][%timestamp 36]} 21... Rd8 {[%clk 0:07:23.3][%timestamp 190]} 22. Ne5
{[%clk 0:08:26.6][%timestamp 86]} 22... Bxe5 {[%clk 0:07:06.3][%timestamp 170]}
23. dxe5 {[%clk 0:08:25.1][%timestamp 15]} 23... Rdc8 {[%clk
0:06:43.8][%timestamp 225]} 24. Qg5+ {[%clk 0:08:18.6][%timestamp 65]} 24... Kf8
{[%clk 0:06:30.9][%timestamp 129]} 25. Rxc8+ {[%clk 0:08:10.9][%timestamp 77]}
25... Rxc8 {[%clk 0:06:28.6][%timestamp 23]} 26. Nd6 {[%clk
0:08:09.6][%timestamp 13]} 26... Nc6 {[%clk 0:05:50.8][%timestamp 378]} 27. Qf6
{[%clk 0:08:04.1][%timestamp 55]} 27... Rc7 {[%clk 0:05:16.2][%timestamp 346]}
28. h4 {[%clk 0:07:58.2][%timestamp 59]} 28... Qe7 {[%clk 0:04:57.7][%timestamp
185]} 29. Qh8# {[%clk 0:07:55.9][%timestamp 23]} 1-0
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 16:30:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chess/2021/01/08/Another-No-Blunders-Game/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chess/2021/01/08/Another-No-Blunders-Game/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am just too sensitive to animal suffering</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Vegan, and I will remain so for the rest of my life. I haver tried watching some of the Vegan and PETA propaganda videos such as 
Earthlings and (God Forbid) Dominion. I know these things show the brutal truth about slaughter houses but I am just not able to 
tolerate watching so much cruelty to animals. I have watched many horror movies in my life but I have never seen anything as brutal
and cruel as the things shown in these films. Never in my life would I wish for anyone to watch Dominion and I would never ever let a 
child watch such terrible things. I can’t control the world and I can’t control other people but I know in my heart I cannot 
contribute to such horrifying treatment of animals. I know animals die, I know that we die. The problem I have with slaughter houses
is not that animals die in them but rather the excessive cruelty and pain and suffering these animnals undergo in the name of
industrial efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 09:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/vegan/2021/01/08/Animal-Suffering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/vegan/2021/01/08/Animal-Suffering/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Souls of Animals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We need another and a wiser and perhaps a more mystical concept of animals. Remote from universal nature and living by complicated artifice, man in civilization surveys the creature through the glass of his knowledge and sees thereby a feather magnified and the whole image in distortion. We patronize them for their incompleteness, for their tragic fate for having taken form so far below ourselves. And therein do we err. For the animal shall not be measured by man. In a world older and more complete than ours, they move finished and complete, gifted with the extension of the senses we have lost or never attained, living by voices we shall never hear. They are not brethren, they are not underlings: they are other nations, caught with ourselves in the net of life and time, fellow prisoners of the splendour and travail of the earth.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
― Henry Beston, The Outermost House: A Year of Life on the Great Beach of Cape Cod&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/animals/2021/01/05/The-souls-of-animals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/animals/2021/01/05/The-souls-of-animals/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bear and Forbear</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The great stoic Epictetus had a golden saying (that I got a tattoo of) “Bear and Forbear”. Meaning that we had to endure and had to have restraint and discipline in order to have the best life. 
The great stoic Marcus Aurelius said that we must accept that each day we will meet selfish, impertinent and greedy people. His point being that once we expect this and understand it those people and condition will be easier to bear. Today is really pushing me to that limit and I am forced to remind myself multiple times that I should have expected this and I must endure.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 06:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/stoicism/2021/01/05/Bear-and-Forbear/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/stoicism/2021/01/05/Bear-and-Forbear/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aleister Crowley Quote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Crowley is an interesting character and his wisdom has to be taken with a grain of salt in general, but I like this quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/crowley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crowley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/01/04/Alister-Crowley-Quote/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2021/01/04/Alister-Crowley-Quote/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100% Pokemon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I caught this bad boy over the holiday weekend. Kinda useless for PVP but still cool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/delibird100.png&quot; alt=&quot;delibird100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 11:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pokemon/go/2021/01/04/Pokemon-100/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pokemon/go/2021/01/04/Pokemon-100/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My mantra for the New Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 was quite an ordeal. I know that we are not completely out of the woods yet, but I am reminded of the word of Kilgore Trout from the novel Timequake by Kurt Vonnegut. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt; “You were sick, but now you're well again, and there's work to do.”

― Kurt Vonnegut (Kilgore Trout, Timequake&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I think there is a special wisdom in these words that will help us all reach the light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 10:48:44 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2021/01/04/New-Years-Mantra/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2021/01/04/New-Years-Mantra/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
